Kailing (Mark) Ding

Sunnyvale, CA 94085 * (415) 509-9231 * markdingkl@gmail.com * markding.me * linkedin.com/in/kailingding

OBJECTIVE (PERMANENT RESIDENT)

Kailing Ding is a UCSD data scientist with 3+ years of experience in internships, entrepreneurial projects, and Kaggle competition, who is eager for building data product with high social and economic impact in machine learning field.

EDUCATION

University of California San Diego, La Jolla, CA

Major: Data Science

Minor: Entrepreneurship & Innovation

Jun 2021

- Relevant coursework: Machine Learning, Data Visualization, Deep Learning, Data Structures & Algorithms, Hypothesis & Permutation Testing, Database Query, Natural Language Processing
- VP of Technology at Eta Omega Chi

May 2019 - Present

SKILLS

Programming: Python, Java, JavaScript, DB Query, HTML, CSS, Bilingual (Chinese and English)

DS / ML: Supervised Learning, Time-series Forecasting, Model Optimization, Data Viz, Sklearn, Neural Network Web Dev: Git, ReactJs, NodeJs, ExpressJs, SQL, MongoDB, AWS EC2/Route 53, Redux, Interactive charts

EXPERIENCES

UCSD Triple C, San Diego, California

Full-Stack Data Scientist (Python, JavaScript)

Jan 2019 – Present

- Lead a Scrum team to develop a sales forecasting product for college markets that reduces unproduced waste and improve efficiencies of markets' supply chain. (Dashboard-liked Web App)
- Implemented **Long Short-term Memory (LSTM) algorithm** for predicting product sales using features such as historical sales data, day and week in the quarter, and large school events.
- Used **ReactJS** for frontend components, **ExpressJS** for web app server, **MongoDB** for databases.
- Utilized multiple charting libraries such as *Highcharts* and *D3* for charts in the dashboard.

GAC Group, Sunnyvale, California

Data Science Intern (Python)

Jun 2019 – *Sep* 2019

- Developed and optimized the prediction model for the health of electric cars' battery with an accuracy score of 88% by engineering features using Sklearn.
- Create **time-series data visualization** based on the vehicle's sensor data that helped the team determine **important features** for modeling.
- Consolidated the stability of regression model by writing production-quality unit tests for data preprocessing and model training within the pipeline using *unittest* module.
- Achieved high accuracy (f1_score of over 0.95) in **detecting anomalous driving behaviors** by building an **unsupervised learning** model based on the *Local Outlier Factor* algorithm.
- Presented complex technical information in a clear and concise manner to other non-technical colleagues.

ENTREPRENUERIAL PROJECTS

2nd Place in UCSD DataHacks 2020

Feb 2020 - Feb 2020

- Acquired 2nd place out of nearly 300 participants in UCSD annual data-centric hackathon.
- Implemented multiple time-series forecasting algorithms to predict UBER travel time in San Francisco.
- Conducted a business analysis report (with features recommendation) for UBER to enhance both user experiences and customer loyalties.

Masterofclass (www.masterofclass.com)

Sep 2019 - Jan 2020

- Built a website that allows college students to search their course group chat QR codes. (~1000 users)
- Implemented MERN stack for this application and deployed this app on AWS EC2.